(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
常闇トワ 1周年記念 BANDLIVE
Tokoyami Towa 1st Anniversary BANDLIVE
2020/01/03 DEBUT DATE
2020/3/3 1ST COVER SONG brilliant
2021/2/25 1ST ORIGINAL SONG Palette
HOLOLIVE 4TH GEN
常闇トワ
Tokoyami Towa
Are You Ready?
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hi! Hi! Hi! Hi!
こんまつり！夏色まつりです！
Konmatsuri! It's Natsuiro Matsuri!
こんやっぴー！常闇トワです！
Konyappi! It's Tokoyami Towa!
よろしくお願いします！
Nice to meet you all!
ご機嫌いかがですか？
How are you doing today?
顔を見れば一瞬でわかるよ
I can tell in an instant just by looking at your face
Shake it!, shake it! メソメソ泣いて
Shake it!, shake it! Sobbing and crying
退屈から恵まれたるかい？
Have you been blessed by boredom?
判定は審議の連続で
The judgment is a continuous series of deliberations
Viva la Sati
踊る街並み Perfect Euphoria
The dancing cityscape, Perfect Euphoria
なんでもないような言葉まで泣いたりするし
I even cry at words that seem like nothing
ほら 僕たちなんて
Look, people like us
全然不向きだね
Are totally unsuited for this
全然お呼びじゃない
Not invited at all
サイコロをまかせて スーパーロックスター
Leave it to the dice, Super Rockstar
オリオンをなぞる こんな深い夜に
Tracing Orion on such a deep night
つながりたい 離されたい
I want to be connected, I want to be separated
座り端、端、端、あちこち
Sitting edge to edge, here and there
新未来を願う
Wishing for a new future
空想の言葉が もしもし
If the words of fantasy, hello hello
紡げるなら 時間が止まるよ
If I can weave them, time will stop
ここで終わるはずがないのに
Even though it shouldn't end here
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hi! Hi! Hi! Hi!
盛り上がっていこう！
Let's get hyped!
Yeah!
ライブは楽しんだもん勝ち！ありがとう！
The one who enjoys the live wins! Thank you!
最新の技術に感謝
Grateful for the latest technology
盛大な発表に乾杯
Cheers to the grand announcement
Shake it!, shake it! 今は何度目？
Shake it!, shake it! What number is this now?
退屈から歌を歌うのか？
Do you sing songs because you're bored?
大天才だって言わなくていい
You don't have to say I'm a great genius
Viva la Sati
確かな感動 Perfect Euphoria
A certain emotion, Perfect Euphoria
切っても切れないんだ
It's an inseparable bond
いい加減 そろそろわかってよ
Listen up, it's about time you understood
さあ 右手を伸ばして
Now, stretch out your right hand
シャッテロマ
Shatteroma
暗闇の底
From the bottom of the darkness
望まぬサインなし
No unwanted signs
最高なままで 軽くテンションMAX!
Staying at our best, tension's slightly MAX!
最後には笑えるくらいの不自由を
An inconvenience we can laugh at in the end
夢を見て 恋をして 呆れるような日々を歌う
Singing of days where we dream and fall in love
ナイフを持つ その本当の意味が
The true meaning of holding a knife
あなたにも もしもしわかるのなら すごく嬉しいんだ
If you, by any chance, understand it, I'd be so happy
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hey! Hey! Hey!
パーフェクトユフォリア さあ凝った文章
Perfect euphoria, now, a sophisticated sentence
パーフェクトユフォリア 最後は僕がいないよ
Perfect euphoria, in the end, I won't be here
光る声は 軽くなって
The shining voices grow light
宙に浮いて
Floating in the air
はるか遠くへ
To somewhere far away
オリオンをなぞる こんな深い夜に
Tracing Orion on such a deep night
繋がりたい 離されたい
Wanting to connect, wanting to be pulled apart
つまり半信半疑 あっちこっち
In other words, half-doubting, here and there
新未来を願うくせ 全然言葉が もしもし紡げるなら 時間が止まるよ
While wishing for a new future, if words can at all be spun, time will stop
オリオンをなぞる こんな深い夜に
Tracing Orion on such a deep night
僕がいて あなたがいて
I am here, you are here
それだけで十分じゃんか
Isn't that enough?
新未来を願うくせ 全然言葉が もしもし紡げるなら
While wishing for a new future, if words can at all be spun
一緒に飛ばそうよ
Let's fly away together
昨日までをちゃんと愛して
Loving everything up until yesterday
見たことのない景色を見るよ
We'll see sights we've never seen before
ここで終わるはずがないのに
Even though it's not supposed to end here
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hey! Hey! Hey!
ヤーイ！
Yay!
はーい！ということで皆さんこんやっぴー！
Hi! So, everyone, Kon-yappi!
ホロライブ4期生の常闇トワです！イエーイ！
I'm Tokoyami Towa from Hololive 4th Gen! Yay!
そして最初のゲストはReACTから獅子神レオナ様！
And the first guest is Shishigami Leona from ReACT!
はーい！こんにちはこんばんは、おはようございます！
Hi! Hello, good evening, good morning!
ReACT所属のVTuber、獅子神レオナです！イエーイ！
I'm the ReACT VTuber, Shishigami Leona! Yay!
やばい、なんかさ、トワさ、なんか今なつーいってなった、なんか。
Man, somehow, I... I felt nostalgic just now.
なんでなんでなんで？
Why, why, why?
トワは、あのレオぴとね、あん、Apexとかやったことあって。
I've played Apex and stuff with Leo-pi before.
うん、そうだね。
Yeah, that's right.
でも歌をこうやってコラボするのが初めてで。
But this is our first time doing a singing collab.
そうね、初めてだわ。
You're right, it's the first time.
いや、あのトワ、レオぴの歌ね、いっぱい聴いてて、すごい大好きなんね。
I mean, I've listened to your songs a lot, I really love them.
歌ってるVTuberさんで、こうやって呼んで、来てくれたこと感謝です。
Among singing VTubers, I'm so grateful you came when I called.
そんな、改まらないでよ、なんか、こっちまでなんかすごい…
Don't be so formal, it's making me feel all...
いやいや、お呼びいただきまして、ありがとうございます。
No, no, thank you so much for inviting me.
いや、なんかあのさ、「パーフェクトユフォリア」とか交わそうねみたいな、お互いこうやって向き合おうねみたいなこと言ってて。
Well, we talked about "exchanging perfect euphoria" and facing each other like this.
向き合った時に、なんかトワ照れちゃった。
When we faced each other, I got a bit shy.
なんで！なんで照れちゃったの？
Why! Why did you get shy?
嬉しいと思って、いや一緒に歌ってくれてありがとう。
I was just so happy. Thanks for singing with me.
いやありがとう、楽しいね、やっぱりこういう盛り上がる曲はね。
No, thank you. It's fun, isn't it? These high-energy songs.
見て、てかさ、トワとさ、レオぴさ、服装ね。
Look, I mean, our outfits, Leo-pi.
そうだよね。結構似てるよね。
Yeah. They're quite similar.
めっちゃシナジーない？
Don't we have great synergy?
ちょっとスクショして、ほら。
Take a screenshot, come on.
イエーイ！
Yay!
ちょっとズームして、ズームズームして。
Zoom in a bit, zoom, zoom.
あ、お小詰め？
Ah, the "oko-zume" pose?
あ、こうか。
Ah, like this.
あ、いい感じ！イエーイ！
Oh, looks good! Yay!
じゃあね、レオぴには、一回バイバイしてもらって。
So, let's say bye to Leo-pi for now.
で、ちょっとおねしんしようかな。
And I think I'll take a little nap.
え、寝ちゃうの？
Eh, you're gonna sleep?
すやーしとこうかな。
I'll just go "suyaa".
じゃあ次の曲に行きたいと思います。レオぴおやすみ。
Then, let's move on to the next song. Night, Leo-pi.
すやーすやーすやー…
Suyaa, suyaa, suyaa...
はーい！ということで2曲目はすいちゃん！
Hi! So the second song is with Sui-chan!
イエーイ！躍らせていこう！
Yay! Let's get moving!
交わしたはずのない約束が
The promise we never should've made
今日も僕らの未来を…
Is once again our future today...
...奪い去る
...take it away
欲しがっていたものを手にしても
Even if I get what I've been wanting
素直にうまく笑えないのはなぜだろう
Why can't I just smile honestly?
溢れる涙は弱さや後悔じゃない
The overflowing tears aren't from weakness or regret
痛みが産んだカケラで
They're fragments born from pain
どんな瞬間だって運命だって
No matter the moment, no matter the fate
ひとつだけ確かなものがあると知った
I've learned that there's one thing I can be sure of
ひとりで考えちゃって今を迷うより
Rather than being lost in the present, thinking alone
明日を迎えに行くんだ
I'm going to go out and meet tomorrow
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
ずっと持ってたい心は地雷
The heart I want to keep forever is a landmine
スイッチは切ってない
The switch isn't turned off
変わらない未来壊したい
I want to destroy the unchanging future
いつも僕を見てるありふれたメロディが
The common melody that's always watching me
くだらないと人に笑われても
Even if people laugh and call it worthless
キラリなおさら輝くのはなぜだろう
Why does it sparkle and shine even more?
何が本当で嘘か理屈じゃなくて
It's not about logic, what's real or what's a lie
感じていたい心で
I want to feel it with my heart
きっと熱くなって現状だって
It'll surely get heated, even this current situation
ごまかしたくないよ傷ついたとしても
I don't want to fake it, even if I get hurt
わかり合いたいと強く願うほど
The more I strongly wish for us to understand each other
ぶつかることもあるから
The more we might clash
感じて！
Feel it!
もっといけるぞ！
We can do more!
どんな瞬間だって運命だって
No matter the moment, no matter the fate
ひとつだけ確かなものがあると知った
I've learned that there's one thing I can be sure of
限界だって困難だって
Even if there are limits, even if there are difficulties
あきらめたくないよこのまま離さないで
I don't want to give up, don't let go of me like this
固く握りしめた君の右手のぬくもり
The warmth of your right hand that I held tight
ここにあるから
It's right here
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
はい、ありがとうございましたー！
Yes, thank you very much!
2曲目はトワの大事な、じゃなくて...
The second song is Towa's precious, I mean...
大好き、大好き、大好き、大好き、大好き、大好き...
I love her, love her, love her, love her...
違うって言ってもあれなんだけど
Even if I say it's different, it's...
大好きな、すごい尊敬してるすいちゃんが来てくれました！
My favorite, whom I highly respect, Sui-chan is here!
わー！ありがと呼んでくれて！
Yay! Thanks for inviting me!
彗星のごとく現れたスターの原石！アイドルVTuberの星街すいせいでーす！
A diamond in the rough who appeared like a comet! I'm the idol VTuber, Hoshimachi Suisei!
いえーい！えー、ちょっとお水飲んじゃおうかな？
Yay! Er, I think I'll have some water.
え、じゃあすいちゃんも飲んじゃおうかな。
Oh, then I'll have some too.
二人で一緒に飲むと無言になるっていうね。
They say when two people drink together, they fall silent.
二人で一緒に飲んだら、二倍味が美味しくなるっていう...
But they also say when two people drink together, it tastes twice as good...
そうでもない。
Not really.
はい！トワの、すいちゃんのなんか、50万人記念の枠で初めてデュエットして
Yes! On Suisei's 500k subscribers stream, we duetted for the first time...
プラトニック・ガールをやって...
We performed "Platonic Girl"...
きた！うん。
It's here! Yeah.
でも、トワの配信では一回もコラボしたことなかったんですよ！
But we've never collaborated on Towa's channel before!
そうなんですよ、実はね！実は！実は！
That's right, actually! Actually! Actually!
だから今日はこうやって来てくれて一緒に歌えたことがとってもハッピー！
So I'm very happy that you could come and sing with me today!
私も嬉しい、私も嬉しい。
I'm happy too, I'm happy too.
ちょうど最近もね、トワがギターやって、私がベースやって...
Just recently, Towa played guitar and I played bass...
これだったよねトワ、トワこれだったよね。
It was like this, right Towa? You were like this.
こうやって、うおぉー！って。
Like this, "Whoooa!"
次の日めちゃめちゃ筋肉痛になったからね！
My muscles were so sore the next day!
そう言ってた、筋肉痛になったって言ってた。
You did say that, that you got muscle pain.
トワのこの美脚が、筋肉痛！
Towa's beautiful legs were sore!
あれも楽しかったし、今日もすごい楽しかった、一緒に歌えて。
That was fun, and today was really fun too, being able to sing together.
え、でも、あと一曲一緒に歌ってくれますか？
But, will you sing one more song with me?
仕方ないなー。
I guess I have no choice.
え、仕方ない？じゃあいいよ、じゃあ。
Eh, no choice? Fine then.
あ、ごめん、なんでもない、違う！
Ah, sorry, never mind, no!
歌わせてください、お願いします！歌わせてください！
Please let me sing, please! Let me sing!
じゃあね、すいちゃんと、もう一曲コラボするんですが
So, I'm going to do one more collab song with Suisei-chan...
もう一人にも来てもらえたらと思います。
...but I'd also like one more person to join us.
もう一度、来てくれるかな？
Will you join us once more?
来てくれるかなー？
Will you join us?
ユーッピー！ハッピー！
Yuppie! Happy!
ゆっくり来ちゃったよ。
I took my sweet time coming out.
ゆっくり来たね。
You certainly did.
待ったよ！
We were waiting!
遅いよ！
You're late!
本当にもう…。
Seriously...
では、まつり殿とのコラボ曲はこちらで最後になるんですけれども
Well, this will be our final collab song with Matsuri-dono...
最後まで、皆さん盛り上がっていける！？
Can everyone stay hyped until the very end!?
イエーイ！盛り上がれー！
Yeah! Get hyped!
じゃあ、みんなで一緒に歌いましょう！
Then, let's all sing together!
せーの！
One, two!
未来はオンナのためにある
The future is for women
The Future belongs to Women
冗談
Joke
やめて
Stop it
止めて
Hold it
マジで
Seriously
無理で
No way
退いて
Move aside
バカにしないで
Don't make a fool of me
Wow...
どっちのセリフなのよ
Which one of us is saying that?
あーちくしょう
Ah, damn it
こんちくしょう
You little brat
どっか消えておくれよ
Just disappear already
夢泥棒
Dream thief
Wow...
お嬢さん 羊の仮面 被った あいつらが
The young ladies... those guys wearing sheep masks...
息潜め 狙いを定め 標的 近付いて来る
Holding their breath, taking aim, the targets are approaching
勘違い野郎 面の皮が 分厚かったら
If those mistaken guys have such thick skins...
ハートの 痛みも分からない
They won't even understand the pain in their hearts
あなた あなた好みのオンナ
You, the kind of woman you like
なんて 笑わせないでよ
Don't make me laugh
ほらね ほらね 噂通りの
See, see, just as the rumors said
ろくでなし
Good-for-nothing
だから
So
オンナたちよ
Women!
声を上げよう
Let's raise our voices
叫び続けよう
Let's keep on shouting
たった一つだけしか 真実はないのよ ごらん
Look, there's only one single truth
ハラハラして
Being on edge
クラクラさせて
Making heads spin
惚れ惚れしちゃう 乙女の勇姿が
A maiden's heroic figure makes me fall in love
けして けして
Never, never
屈しはしないはずだわ
I will never yield
だらしないとは 言わせない
I won't let you say I'm slovenly
言わせたって 構わない
Even if you say so, I don't care
冗談
Joke
やめて
Stop it
止めて
Hold it
マジで
Seriously
無理で
No way
退いて
Move aside
バカにしないで
Don't make a fool of me
Wow...
お姉さん こんがらがった 罠にはまってない？
Big sister, aren't you caught in a tangled trap?
飴玉のような ささやきと 打ち身みたいな 接吻を
Whispers like candy and kisses like bruises
意気地なし野郎 焼きも 焼けない嘘つきには
For a spineless guy, a liar who can't even get jealous...
涙の 意味さえ分からない
They don't even understand the meaning of tears
お前 お前一人のものだ
You're mine and mine alone
なんて 出直してきてよ
Come back when you've rethought that
あのね あのね 浅はかすぎる
Listen, listen, you're just too shallow
エゴイスト
Egoist
だから
So
オンナたちよ
Women!
自由になれ
Be free
鎖を解いて
Break the chains
たった一度だけしか 人生にはないから 見せて
Since you only have one life, show me
ドキドキして
Making hearts throb
クラクラさせて
Making heads spin
虜にしちゃう しびれる覚悟を
Enthralling me with your electrifying resolve
きっと きっと
Surely, surely
うねりに変わるはずだわ
It will turn into a swell
この手でずっと 感じたい
I want to keep feeling it with these hands
どこまでだって 愛したい
I want to love you to the ends of the earth
冗談
Joke
やめて
Stop it
止めて
Hold it
マジで
Seriously
無理で
No way
退いて
Move aside
バカにしないで
Don't make a fool of me
Wow...
盛り上がっていこうぜー！
Let's get hyped!
最後まで！
Until the end!
行くぜ！
Let's go!
一人では
By myself...
小さな声 かき消されてしまうけれど
...my small voice would get drowned out...
強い声 海を越え
...but a strong voice, crossing the sea...
涙を
Tears...
未来は
The future...
すべて
...is all...
私たちの
...for...
ためにある
...us.
だからオンナたちよ
So, women...
声をあげよう
...raise your voices...
叫び続けよう
...and keep on screaming!
たった一つだけしか 真実は ないのよ
There is only one single truth!
ごらん ごらん
Look, look!
ハラハラして
Being on edge...
フラフラさせて
...making them dizzy...
ホレホレしちゃう乙女の美学
...it's the aesthetic of a girl who'll make you fall in love!
消して 消して
Erase it, erase it...
許しはしないはずだわ
...you're not supposed to forgive!
待ってなんていられない
I can't wait!
誰のせいだってかまわない
I don't care whose fault it is!
衝動
Impulse!
止めて
Stop!
マジで
Seriously!
無理で
Impossible!
どいて馬鹿にしないで
Get out of the way, don't mock me!
wow... こっちのセリフなのよ
wow... that's my line!
アンチクショウ コンチクショウ
That damn... This damn...!
どこか消え失せろよ 夢泥棒
Get lost somewhere, you dream thief!
最後みんなで跳ぶよ！
We'll all jump at the end!
跳ぶよ！
Jump!
せーの！
Ready, set...
ジャンプ！
Jump!
はい、ということで！
Okay, and with that!
Re:AcTから獅子神レオナちゃんと
From Re:AcT, Shishigami Leona-chan...
ホロライブから星街すいせい先輩
...and from Hololive, Hoshimachi Suisei-senpai.
すい先輩、すいせー
Sui-senpai, Suisei...
三ちゃん、ちゃんちゃんで
San-chan, Chan-chan...
すいちゃん
Sui-chan...
普通に行こうかな
Maybe I'll just go with the normal one.
星街さんちゃん
Hoshimachi San-chan.
なんでしっくり来てねぇんだよ
Why doesn't that feel right?
先輩ちゃん、すいちゃん
Senpai-chan, Sui-chan...
すいちゃんでスゴいしっくりきてるからフルネームって
"Sui-chan" feels so right, so when you use the full name...
が、来てくれました！
...they've come to join me!
はい、ありがとうございました！
Yes, thank you very much!
スゴい楽しかった！
That was so much fun!
よかったね！
It was great!
楽しくて歌うと、どんどん何か「わー！」ってなっちゃった
Singing was so fun that I just got all "Waa!"
アドレナリンが！
The adrenaline!
もうこれはトワの思い出です。ありがとう！
This is a precious memory for Towa. Thank you!
いやいや、こちらこそ思い出！
No, no, it's a memory for us too!
おめでとうございます！
Congratulations!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
ということで、ここでゲストのコーナーは おしまいです！
And with that, the guest corner comes to an end!
二人は... 二人とも、じゃあトワのこと、あとで見守っててね
You two... both of you, please watch over Towa later, okay?
わかった！
Got it!
あっちで、あっちで見守るね、あっちから。
We'll watch over you from over there.
お疲れ様です！
Great job!
はい、じゃあみんな、バイバイ！
Okay, then, everyone, bye-bye!
すいちゃん、レオナちゃん、サンキュー！
Sui-chan, Leona-chan, thank you!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
カワキヲアメク / 作詞・作曲 美波
Kawaki wo Ameku / Written & Composed by Minami
未熟
Immature.
無情
Heartless.
されど
Yet...
美しくあれ
...be beautiful.
眩しい 苦騒がしくない
It's dazzling, not noisy.
こんなんじゃ 物足りないくらい 語ってけば上手くいく
If I talk enough to make this feel insufficient, it'll go well.
物金 愛 ごっこ
Playing with things, money, and love.
もう自己顕示 飽きた
I'm already tired of self-display.
既読が何がそんな不満なんだ 散々わがまま語っておいて
What are you so dissatisfied with the "read" receipt for? After all your selfishness...
これ以上他に何がいる そんなところも 割り切れないじゃない
...what else do you need? I can't even justify that side of you.
もう聞き飽きたんだよ そのセリフ
I'm already tired of hearing those lines.
中途半端で食えばいい
You should just eat them halfway.
もういいよ そうして 言ってたって
It's enough, even if you keep saying that...
愛してるって 言われたって
...even if you keep saying "I love you"...
遊びだけなら簡単で
...it's easy if it's just a game.
真剣交渉 無茶苦茶で
Serious negotiations are a mess.
思いもしない重い言葉なんて
Such heavy words that I didn't even expect...
使い古すのか
...will you use them until they're worn out?
どうせ期待してたんだ できレース
I was expecting a rigged race anyway.
引用だらけのフレーズも
Phrases full of citations...
かかと持ち上げること言葉に
...and words that lift up your heels...
して空気も読まずに膨らまないでよ
...don't go bloating without reading the room.
カワキをアメク
Crying for Rain
窓を越して　話を止めよう
Stop talking through the window.
行き止まり　最低で　運命に　もじらないでどうぞ
A dead end, the worst, please don't play with fate.
いじらないでどうぞ
Please don't mess with it.
変な安堵状は　何度目？　もう僕なら
How many times for this strange letter of relief? If it's me...
脆いセンス広げる　その方が魅力的でしょう？
Spreading a fragile sense, isn't that more attractive?
愛でた　変えられないなら　放っといてくれ
If what I loved can't be changed, then leave me alone.
迷えるなら　そっとしてくれ
If I can wander, then leave me be.
肝心なところは　筒抜けで
The essential parts are leaking out.
安心だけは　させられるような
As if you could make me feel safe.
甘い雨が降れば
If sweet rain falls...
傘も差したくなるだろう
You'll want to hold an umbrella, right?
このまま　大切なことは　何だっけ？
Just like this, what was the important thing again?
目を瞑って　たかった
I wanted to keep my eyes closed.
言の葉　無くした　巻き戻せなかった
Words lost, couldn't rewind.
今　雨止めないで
Right now, don't stop the rain.
止む
Stops.
雨傘を閉じて　濡れて帰ろう
Close the umbrella and go home soaked.
ギラギラ
作詞・作曲：てにをは
Gira Gira
Lyrics & Composition: Teniwoha
嗚呼　本当になって　素晴らしき世界
Ah, becoming real, what a wonderful world.
ねぇもまた　己の醜悪さに　惑う
Hey, I'm wandering in my own ugliness again.
だのに人好きで　想う気持ちだけは
And yet, I like people, and just these feelings...
一丁前にあるから　悶えるんでしょう
...are so fully grown that they make me writhe.
嗚呼　虹を弾いて　私の顔は
Ah, repelling the rainbow, my face...
神様が左手で　描いたみたい
...looks like God drew it with his left hand.
必然　この世にあるラブソングは　どれ一つ
Inevitably, not a single love song in this world...
絶対　私向けなんかじゃないでしょう
...is definitely meant for me, right?
使い道のない　口づけ
A kiss with no use.
憐れみを　欲しいままに
Indulging in pity.
スポットライトに　歌われ身を守る
Sung to by the spotlight, protecting myself.
愛されないくらいなんだ
So what if I'm not loved?
ギラギラ輝いて　私は夜を呑む
Glittering brightly, I swallow the night.
ラップ・タップ・タップ・タップ　今に見テロ　このLOVE
Rap tap tap tap, just you watch, this LOVE.
噛み締める唇　裏の鼓動ビートル
Biting my lip, the heartbeat inside like a beetle.
オー・オー・オー　なんて不気味　この世は美だ
Oh-oh-oh, how eerie, this world is beauty.
ギラ　ギラギラ　ギラ
Gira, gira-gira, gira
嗚呼　お釈迦様も　存ぜぬうちに
Ah, even Buddha, while he wasn't looking.
鮮やかに振る舞っていたい
I want to behave brilliantly
それは世界の方？ それとも私の方ですか？
Is it for the world's sake? Or for mine?
共生は端から無理でしょう
Symbiosis is impossible from the start
まがいものこそ悲しけれ
Fakes are all the more sad
無我夢中　走る　走る
Running, running, lost in the moment
強さが正義なら　洗い流す前に
If strength is justice, before washing it away...
行こう　食欲のあざ抱いて
Let's go, embracing the bruises of desire
メラメラ火を吹いて
Spitting out flaring flames
私は夜の神
I am the god of the night
ラッパッパ　そこで見てろこの乱舞
Rap-pa-pa, watch this wild dance right there
脆くない　あなたなりの名画
Not fragile, a masterpiece in your own way
ラッパッパ　不意にファニー　孤独は solitary
Rap-pa-pa, suddenly funny, loneliness is solitary
いくつな街を行く　目を閉じて
Walking through several towns, closing my eyes
もう一回　もう一回
One more time, one more time
もしも神様が左利きなら
If God were left-handed...
どんなに幸せか　しれない
I don't know how happy I'd be
ギラギラ輝いて
Sparkling brightly
私は夜の神
I am the god of the night
ラッパッパ　今に見とけこの乱舞
Rap-pa-pa, watch this wild dance now
噛み締める　1ミリグラムの火花
Savoring a milligram of sparks
ラッパッパ　なんてファニー　これはビター
Rap-pa-pa, how funny, this is bitter
ギラ
Gira
ギラギラ
Gira gira
ギラ
Gira
ギラギラ
Gira gira
ギラ　炎を吐いて
Gira, spitting flames
ありのままじゃいられない
I can't stay as I am
誰も彼も勝手に素晴らしい世界だ
Everyone, in their own way, in this wonderful world
ギラついていこう
Let's keep on sparkling
ハハハハ、はぁ〜はぁ〜はぁ〜しちゃってました〜
Hahahaha, haa~ panting, panting, I was panting~
あっという間に、えー、2曲、えー、今の曲が、やばい、曲名が...
In the blink of an eye, uh, two songs. Uh, the song just now, oh no, the title...
『カワキをアメク』という曲と、さっきの曲が『ギラギラ』という曲でした。
"Kawaki wo Ameku" and the song before that was "Gira Gira."
えー、『カワキをアメク』って曲は...
Uh, the song "Kawaki wo Ameku"...
お水飲む。
I'll drink some water.
みんなで見ないよ。
Don't watch, everyone.
スタッフさんがね、優しく、お水をくれました。感謝！
The staff members, so kindly, gave me some water. Thank you!
いやもう、スタッフさんも、ありがとうございますと、この場をお借りして言わせてもらいます。
And also, I'd like to take this opportunity to thank the staff members as well.
いや、『カワキをアメク』は、あのー、実は、結構前、いつだっけな、の時に、なんか流行りの曲を覚えようみたいな枠をしてて
Well, "Kawaki wo Ameku" is, uh, actually, quite a while ago, I forget when, I did a stream where I tried to learn some popular songs.
そん時に、美波さんの『カワキをアメク』と、『夜に駆ける』を練習して
At that time, I practiced "Kawaki wo Ameku" by Minami and "Yoru ni Kakeru."
『カワキをアメク』はそこじゃな、その枠で覚えた曲なので
I learned "Kawaki wo Ameku" then, during that stream.
こうしてな、ライブでね、みんなに、生音でね、披露できたのが嬉しいなって思います。
So I'm really happy to be able to perform it live with a band for everyone like this.
この曲は生で歌うのがむずい！ 早い！ トワの滑舌 VS 音楽
This song is hard to sing live! It's fast! Towa's enunciation vs. the music.
そんな感じでしたけど、大丈夫だったかな、みんな。見てた？
It was like that, but was it okay, everyone? Were you watching?
ド、ドラム止まれ！ いいの、ドラムはね、いいの、叩かせてあげて、みんなもう、大きな心で叩かせてあげて、ドラムを。
D-Drum, stop! It's okay, let the drums play. Everyone, with a big heart, let the drums play.
叩き出した！ 叩いちゃうから、可愛い。
They started drumming! They're drumming, how cute.
いいんだよ、叩いて。いいんだよ。
It's okay, go ahead and drum. It's okay.
そうそう、で『カワキをアメク』と、さっきの『ギラギラ』はね、あの『うっせぇわ』を、かなたと上げたんですけど、そのAdoさんが歌っている曲になります。
Right, right. So, "Kawaki wo Ameku" and the previous "Gira Gira"... I covered "Usseewa" with Kanata, and this is another song sung by Ado.
ちょっとね、『カワキをアメク』も『ギラギラ』もすごい難しかったんだけど、まあ、うまく歌えたのかな、と思います。
A bit, you know, both "Kawaki wo Ameku" and "Gira Gira" were really difficult, but well, I think I was able to sing them well.
もう色んな曲を歌ってきたんで、で、結構激しい曲と、まあなんだろう、難しい曲と流行りの曲と歌ったんで
I've sung a lot of songs already, and I've sung some pretty intense ones, well, some difficult ones and popular ones.
次は、あの、しっとりした曲を歌おうかなって思っております。
Next, uh, I'm thinking of singing a mellow song.
みんなもね、休憩タイム、心穏やかにしましょう。
Everyone, it's break time, let's calm our hearts.
では、次の曲、しっとりした曲、聞いてください。『Wherever you are』
Then, the next song, a mellow song, please listen. "Wherever you are."
Wherever you are
作詞・作曲: Taka
Lyrics/Music: Taka
I tell you...
Oh yeah
I softy whisper
Tonight, tonight
You are my angel
愛してるよ
I love you
Oh yeah
二人は一つに
The two of us are one
Tonight, tonight
I just say...
Wherever you are, I'll always make you smile
Wherever you are, I'm always by your side
Whatever you say, 君を思う気持ち
Whatever you say, my feelings for you
I promise you "forever" right now
I don't need a reason
Oh yeah
I just want you baby
Alright, alright
Day after day
この先長いことずっと
For a long time from now on
どうかこんな僕とずっと
Please stay with me forever
死ぬまで...
Until I die...
Stay with me
We carry on
Wherever you are, I'll always make you smile
Wherever you are, I'm always by your side
Whatever you say, 君を思う気持ち
Whatever you say, my feelings for you
I promise you "forever" right now
Wherever you are, I'll never make you cry
Wherever you are, I'll never say goodbye
Whatever you say, 君を思う気持ち
Whatever you say, my feelings for you
I promise you "forever" right now
僕らが出会った日は
The day we met
二人にとって一番目の記念すべき日だね
Is the first day to celebrate for both of us
そして今日という日は
And today as a day
二人にとって二番目の記念すべき日だね
Is the second day to celebrate for both of us
心から愛せる人
Someone I can love from the bottom of my heart
心から愛おしい人
Someone who is truly dear to me
この僕の愛の真ん中には
At the center of my love
いつも君がいるから
Because you're always there
Wherever you are, I'll always make you smile
Wherever you are, I'm always by your side
Whatever you say, 君を思う気持ち
Whatever you say, my feelings for you
I promise you "forever" right now
Wherever you are
ちょっと待っててね！
Please wait a bit!
やー！ホロアリーナ！
Yeah! Holo Arena!
ばーじょん、ばんっど、ばーじょん？っていいんか？
Version... band... version... is that okay to say?
やべ、一人だから誰かツッコミがーっていうのは、まあいいとして。
Oops, I'm alone so there's no one to do a tsukkomi... well, anyway.
ということで。みなさん、ありがとうございましたー！
With that said... thank you everyone!
どうでしたでしょうか？
How was it?
トワも、このステージでこのアイドル衣装をみんなに見せんのって、初めてな気がする。どーお？
I feel like it's the first time I've shown everyone this idol costume on this stage. How is it?
いえーい！
Yay!
悪魔だよ。ほら。ちゃんとついてるでしょ、この何これ？
I'm a devil! See? These are properly attached... what are these?
ちょっと語彙力が消失してる。語彙力ー！おいでー。
My vocabulary has vanished. Vocabulary! Come back!
どうでした？
How was it?
いやあね、本当、トワの今日、4月17日、ね、トワの1周年記念配信をしてるんですけれども、
Seriously, today, April 17th, I'm doing Towa's 1st anniversary stream,
本当は1月3日にデビューしてます。
but I actually debuted on January 3rd.
で、なんでこのちょっと日程がズレちゃったのかっていうと、トワちょっと生音で、
The reason why the date shifted is because I wanted a live performance,
あの8月の誕生日の時には、あの、アコースティックで生音でやって、
and for my birthday in August, I did a live acoustic performance,
やっぱ生音っていいなーって、すごい思ったので。
and I thought 'Live audio is so great!'
バンドでね、ちょっとやりたいなーと。
So I wanted to do it with a band.
バンドでやりたいなーってもう本当に、もうやってくれてるんですよ、バンド。ほら。
I really wanted to do it with a band. And look, they're already doing it!
こむくんも、もうやってて、もう気持ちいいよね。やっぱりな。
Comu-kun is already at it, it feels good, doesn't it? Just as I thought.
トワ、アコースティックも好評で、
The acoustic set was also well-received,
そう、あの、もうできることならばバンドで、ドラムと、ほら、ベースと、ギターと。これで生音でやりたいなーという風に、
so I thought 'If possible, I want to do it live with a band, with drums, bass, and guitar.'
運営さんにお願いして。
So I asked the staff.
そしたらちょっと1月3日にはちょっと機材がどうしても、ちょっと大掛かりなもんで、と言って。
They said that for January 3rd, the equipment would be too much of a major undertaking.
あの、じゃあ、でもどうしてもやりたいんです、トワは。もう1月3日じゃなくて、準備万端の時にやります！って言って。
But I said 'I really want to do it. So I'll do it when I'm fully prepared, not on January 3rd!'
じゃあ、そうしましょう！と言って、今日はね、この素敵な後ろで、
So they agreed! And today, with these wonderful people in the back...
ほら、ずっと叩いてるでしょ。ずっと弾いてるし。
See? They've been playing all along! They've been playing the whole time!
それ！うわー！トワ！テンション最高潮ー！
There it is! Whoa! My tension is at its peak!
そう、でこの生音でやることができました。
So, I was able to do this with live audio.
もう本当にありがとうございます。皆さんのおかげです。ありがとうございます。
Thank you so much! It's all thanks to everyone. Thank you.
でもね、みんなね、ツイッターとかね、エゴサしててもね、トワ様のグッズはいつ来るの？という風な形で、よく見たんですよ。
But you know, when I was vanity searching on Twitter, I often saw people asking 'When are Master Towa's goods coming?'
では、なんと！あります！トワの1周年グッズ発売します！
Well, believe it or not, I have them! Towa's 1st anniversary goods are going on sale!
常闇トワ 活動一周年記念
4月17日 販売開始
Tokoyami Towa Activity 1st Anniversary
Sales start April 17th
どどーん。見て、あ、来た。
Ta-da! Look! Oh, there it is.
活動一周年記念。トワ様の記念ボイス全部セット、記念グッズ3種セット。これですね。
Activity 1st Anniversary. Master Towa's Memorial Voice Full Set, Memorial Goods 3-piece Set. This is it.
まずはね、ボイスはね、まあ聴いてもらって。
First, for the voice set, please listen to it.
記念グッズ3種セットっていうのが、こちらです。
The memorial goods 3-piece set is this.
あ、間違えた。タペストリーがこちらです。じゃじゃーん！
Oh, I made a mistake. The tapestry is this! Ta-da!
見た？どう、
Did you see? How is it?
可愛くない？るるど様ママが描いてくれたの。ママ見てるー？いえーい！
Isn't it cute? Rurudo-mommy drew it for me. Mommy, are you watching? Yay!
可愛いでしょ、これ。
It's cute, right?
で、何これ。ね。ちょっと、これはちょっとあんまり、なんか、みんな妄想しないで待ってもらって。
And what is this? Well... please don't fantasize too much about this...
可愛いでしょー。このタペストリーと、あと、もう一つです。どーん。
It's cute, isn't it? This tapestry and... one more. Ta-da!
「ビビ」モチーフ ぬいぐるみクッション
"Bibi"-motif Plushie Cushion
じゃじゃーん！ビビのモチモチモチモチモチのぬいぐるみクッション！
Ta-da! Bibi's squishy-squishy-squishy-squishy plushie cushion!
これな、これぐらいで、
This, it's about this big,
ね、わかったかな？トワの体で。これぐらいで、ね、これぐらいかな。
see? Get it compared to Towa's body? It's about this big, yeah, around this size.
ですごいモチモチしてんの、モチモチ。
And it's really squishy, squishy.
もうこれね、今しかないです。皆さん。
This is only available now, everyone.
今しかないです。
Only now.
こちら！今しかないですよ！
This! It's only available now!
やばい、この格好でやるもんじゃない。今しかないですよ！はい。
Oh man, I shouldn't be doing this in this outfit. It's only available now! Yes.
はい。えー、こちらが、えーと、あの概要欄にね、もう買えるの更新されてます。
Yes. Um, this, uh, the link to buy it is already updated in the description.
でもあと待ってくださいね、
But wait,
一個あるんです。ドーン！
there's one more thing. Bam!
はい、見て！トワのモチーフデザインキーホルダー！
Yes, look! Towa's motif design keychain!
「常闇トワ」モチーフデザインキーホルダー
"Tokoyami Towa"-motif Design Keychain
これあれだよ。
This is that.
あの、これは今アイドル衣装なんだけど、
Um, I'm in my idol outfit now,
通常のね、あのお洋服のね、こっちにあるね、
but the keychain on my regular clothes...
このキーホルダーがなんと実物になってしまいました！
it's actually become a real product!
Oh my god! そう、実物になっちゃったんです。
Oh my god! Yes, it's become real.
もうこれも今しかないよ、みんな。
This is also only available now, everyone.
安いよ、安いよ、今しかないよ、とか言って。
It's cheap, it's cheap, only now, I say.
で、これを全部買ってくれた人には、特典の、ドーン！
And for those who buy the whole set, as a bonus, bam!
記念グッズ&記念ボイス 全部セット特典
Commemorative Goods & Voices Full Set Bonus
イラストポストカード！トワのサイン入り、複製サイン入りのポストカードが絶対ついてくるよ。キラキラー。
An illustration postcard! It comes with a postcard with Towa's printed signature. Sparkle!
ということなので、ぜひ、どれもね、これもめちゃめちゃいいので、ぜひ、お願いします。
So please, all of them, this too, they're really great, so please, check them out.
ページはね、あの今もう見れるんだけど、発売は21時、配信が終わった後に買えるようになるので。
The page, you can see it now, but sales start at 21:00, you can buy them after the stream ends.
もう、海外のアニキも、この、ね、日本のアニキも、もうオーバーシーも、みんな。
Overseas bros, Japanese bros, everyone overseas, everyone...
トワのことを大好きでいてください！イェーイ！
please keep loving Towa! Yay!
みんなちゃんと呟いた？これ。#常闇トワ1周年記念
Did everyone tweet about this? #TokoyamiTowa1stAnniversary
呟いてくれた？呟いてくれたら嬉しいな。
Did you tweet? I'd be happy if you did.
はい。ということでね、まあ、お水を飲んで、
Alright. With that said, well, let me drink some water...
トワはね、マイペースに、やっていきたいです。これからも。
Towa wants to keep doing things at her own pace. From now on too.
今までもね、マイペースやらせてもらったんだけど、
I've been doing things at my own pace until now,
あったかい眷属に包まれながら、これからもトワのペースでやっていけたらと思います。
and surrounded by my warm Kenzoku, I hope to continue at Towa's pace.
みんな本当にいつもありがとう！
Thank you so much always, everyone!
ということで、次、二曲聴いてください。
So, please listen to the next two songs.
最後の二つになります。よろしくお願いします。
These will be the last two. Thank you.
では、ニケさんの、Hearts。
Now, "Hearts" by Nike-san.
昨日日々が　さよならを告げて
The days of yesterday bid farewell
輝いてまた消えるよ
Shining, then vanishing again
思い出の中で　間違いを恐れ
Inside my memories, fearing mistakes
許されてきたはずでしょう
I must have been forgiven, right?
東の空　ビルに溶けた
The eastern sky melted into the buildings
風のように
Like the wind
嬉しいこと　悲しいこと
The happy things, the sad things
消して何を残せた？
What could I leave behind by erasing them?
僕が　あなたが　私が　君が
I, you, myself, you...
心に刻む音
The sounds carved into our hearts
何を信じ続けて　感じ続けて
What should I keep believing, keep feeling
ここに立ち憧れてる
Standing here, longing
今　僕は　叫んで　叫んで　触れて
Now, I scream, scream, and touch
この手が縮む音
The sound of this hand shrinking
いつだって聞こえた　ずっと繋いで
I always heard it, connected all along
冷めた心　解かせるよ
It will thaw my frozen heart
いくつもの声が　この空を越えて
Many voices crossing this sky
輝いてまた消えるよ
Shining, then vanishing again
戸惑いの中で　ただ意味を求め
Amidst confusion, simply seeking meaning
試されてゆくはずでしょう
We must be getting tested, right?
ヒラヒラヒラ　ヒラヒラヒラ
Fluttering, fluttering, fluttering...
落ちるように
As if falling
嬉しいこと　悲しいこと
The happy things, the sad things
全て抱いて生きてきた
I've lived embracing them all
僕が　あなたが　生まれた日から
Since the day you and I were born
心に刻む音
The sounds carved into our hearts
何を裏切られて　感じ続けて
By what was I betrayed? I keep feeling
心壊されてゆく
My heart is being broken
今　僕は　叫んで　叫んで　触れて
Now, I scream, scream, and touch
この目に映る音
The sound reflected in these eyes
そうやって生まれた
Born that way,
ちょっと苦しくて
it's a little painful
せめて心
At least
砕かれぬように
so my heart won't be shattered
全て抱いて生きてきた
I've lived embracing everything
僕が あなたが 私が 君が
Me, you, I, you—
心に刻もうと
let's carve it into our hearts
何を信じ続けて
Continuing to believe in something,
感じ続けて
continuing to feel
ここに立ち焦がれてる
Standing here, yearning
今僕は 叫んで 叫んで
Now I'm shouting, shouting
触れて
reaching out
その手が虹を追う
those hands chasing the rainbow
いつだって聞こえた
I always heard it
ずっと繋いで
keep us connected forever
せめて心
At least
砕かれぬように
so my heart won't be shattered
Palette
作詞：常闇トワ 作曲：kous
Lyrics: Tokoyami Towa / Composition: kous
風に吹かれて
Blown by the wind,
誰も気付かぬよう
so no one notices
区別がつかない
In a monochrome world
モノクロの世界
where nothing is distinct
色を足しても
Even adding colors,
何も見えなくて
I couldn't see anything
まるで私は
It was as if
息を止めていた
I was holding my breath
もういいよ 遠くても 叶えたい
It's okay now, even if it's far, I want to make it come true
私は こんな世界
In this kind of world, I—
思いを 抱きしめていたいのに
I want to embrace my feelings, and yet...
夢のキャンバスに 描き続ける意味は
The meaning of continuing to draw on the canvas of dreams
この胸に 輝いているストーリー
Is the story shining within this chest
隠れる心に 意味などないけれど
There's no meaning in a hiding heart, but...
色を見つめた
I gazed at the colors,
変わらないもの
the things that don't change
そして夜は その冷たさを
And so the night melted that coldness,
溶かして手を伸ばした
and I reached out my hand
もういいよ 遠くても 届きたい
It's okay now, even if it's far, I want to reach it
私は 受け止めていく
I will accept it all
涙も 抱きしめていたいのに
Even the tears, I want to embrace them, and yet...
夢のキャンバスに 心込めるのは
Putting my heart into the canvas of dreams
この空に 描き出していくストーリー
Is the story I'm drawing across this sky
そして夜は その冷たさを
And so the night melted that coldness,
溶かして手を伸ばした
and I reached out my hand
もういいの 遠くても 叶えたい
It's enough now, even if it's far, I want to fulfill it
私の この世界
this world of mine
想いを 言葉で綴った
I composed my feelings into words
夢のキャンバスに 色を足していく
Adding colors to the canvas of dreams
この胸に 今輝いて
Shining in my chest right now
強くなくてもいい
It's okay if I'm not strong,
壊れかけてもいい
it's okay if I'm falling apart
この心は解き放たれて
This heart is being set free
響くように 塗り替えていくパレット
Repainting the palette so that it resonates
Palette / 常闇トワ
Palette / Tokoyami Towa
みんなー、サンキュー！
Everyone, thank you!
大好きだよー！
I love you all!
ありがとー！
Thank you!
常闇トワ 1周年記念 BANDLIVE
Tokoyami Towa 1st Anniversary BANDLIVE